Hussaini Mohd Marsidi

Graduate Engineer

Johor Bahru, Johor | 019-872 4370 | hussainimarsidi@gmail.com

Career Objective

A 23-years old mechanical engineering graduate developed interest in application development and database architecture. Seeking for progressive organization that provides **opportunity to capitalize my technical skills in field of information Technology (IT).** Currently, work as part-time freelancer in small team related to mobile apps development and research assistant in Faculty of Computing, UTM Skudai. I enjoy working with startups and established companies.

Professional Experience

Research Assistant

2018 - Present

Universiti Teknologi Malaysia (UTM), Johor

Served as a key member of the research team of Research Alliance: Smart Digital Community initiative. In charged of formulating strategic direction and devising technical requirement for development initiatives consistent with overall strategy. Planned and executed technical solution to troubleshoot issues related to mobile development in Angular and React Native frameworks as well as humanoid robots. Managed events and training for new recruits. Sole developer of iCare English Apps in the same initiative.

- 1. Create iCareEnglishApp to help students from rural area to learn English grammar in Malay language.
- 2. Introduced React Native framework that is more robust and lightweight, speed up the production time.
- 3. Assigned to troubleshoot hardware and software related to all humanoid robot under Smart Digital Community project.

Internships

June 2019 - August 2019

Enigma Technical Solutions Sdn Bhd, Perak

Type of Business: Intergrated Logistic Support (ILS), Marine Industry

- 1. Working with the team during troubleshooting process on ships
- 2. Conducted research and documentation for outsourcing segment of business
- 3. Designing and maintaining websites and social media sites

Education

Universiti Teknologi Malaysia (UTM)

Bachelor of Mechanical Engineering

CGPA: 2.98

Kelantan Matriculation College

Science

CGPA: 3.96

2015 - 2019

2014 - 2015

Internet of Things (IoT)



Arduino

Mobile Apps Developer (Client-Side)



- President Entrepreneurial
 Club
- Head of Department Festival Konvokesyen UTM 2017
- Research Team Research Alliance: Smart Digital Community
- Research Team InMotion
 Summer School on Computer
 Modding and Simulation (CSME)
 Project at St Petersburg
 ,Russia.Co Funded by Erasmus+
 Program of European Union (EU)
- Sponsorships Young Innovate Johor State Level collaboration with Sime Darby

Professional Development

- 1. Huawei Certified ICT Associate (HCIA) Big Data v2.0
- 2. SOLIDWORK (Training Certificate from CadVision)
- Occupational Safety, Health and Environment (OSHE)
- 4. ISO 9001:2008 Quality Management System Requirement

Technical Skills

Reference

Angular Framework

1. Dr Fazila Mohd Zawawi

Academic Advisor, Department of Thermo - Fluid Faculty of Mechanical Engineering Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, 81310 Johor Bahru Johor

Contact No: +6075534614 2. Dr Fazila Mohd Zawawi

Department of Software Engineering Faculty of Computer

Universiti Teknologi Malaysia, 81310 Johor Bahru Johor

Mobile Apps Developer (Client-Side)

React-Native Framework

Web Development (Client-Side)

HTML, CSS, Javascript, Owl and Bootstrap

